Register of the James Harold Shoemaker Papers, 1924-1983
Hoover Institution Archives
James Harold Shoemaker Papers,
1924-1983
84046
Shoemaker, James Harold, 1897-1983
14 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 1 envelope (6.76 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Speeches and writings, correspondence, orders, manuals, printed matter, and photographs, relating to economic warfare during World War II, the bombing of Japan, American military government in Japan and Korea, and the economy of Hawaii.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1984.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
United States. Board of Economic Warfare.; United States Strategic Bombing Survey.; Military government.; World War, 1939-1945.; World War, 1939-1945--Aerial operations.; World War, 1939-1945--Economic aspects.; World War, 1939-1945--Japan.; Hawaii--Economic conditions.; Japan.; Japan--History--Allied occupation, 1945-1952.; Korea.; Korea--History--Allied occupation, 1945-1948.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Armed Forces.; Economists.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
1897 September 10 Born, Dubuque, Iowa
1918 B.A., State College, Iowa
1920-1923 Faculty member, Nagasaki College, Japan
1924 M.A., University of Iowa, Iowa
1924-1928 Instructor, Department of Economics, Brown University, Rhode Island
1928-1931 Faculty member, Harvard University, Massachusetts
1931-1945 Professor of Economics, Brown University
1933, 1935 Research Analyst, Bureau of Labor Statistics, United States Department of Labor (summer months)
1939 Author, Labor in the Territory of Hawaii, 1939
1939, 1947, 1949 Director of Economic Survey of Hawaii, Bureau of Labor Statistics, sponsored by the United States Congress
1940-1943 Consultant, Office of Export Control, United States Government
1941-1942 Deputy Director, Far Eastern Division, United States Government
1942-1943 Director, Enemy Potential Division, Office of Economic Warfare, United States Government
1942-1945 Lieutenant Colonel, War Department, Military Government Division, United States Government
1945-1946 Colonel, United States Strategic Bombing Survey, Japan
1946 Dean, Business School, University of Hawaii
1946 Major General (assimilated rank), United States Navy mission in Japan
1946-1947 Chairman, National Economic Board, United States Military Government in South Korea
1946-1949 Chairman, Economic Department, University of Hawaii
1947 Author, The Economy of Hawaii in 1947
1948-1949 Director, Program Coordinator Division, National Security Resources Board, Executive Office of the President of the United States
1949-1968 Vice President and Director of Business Research, Bank of Hawaii
1950-1953 Consultant, National Security Resources Board (summer months)
1954? Member, United States Civil Service Commission
1958, 1965 Member, Reserve Bank of New Zealand Mission
1958-1960, 1963-1965 President, Pacific and Asian Affairs Council
1958-1970 Trustee, Bernice P. Bishop Museum, Hawaii
1959 Member, Trade missions to Peru and Equador, Trade Development Bureau, United States Department of Commerce
1960 Honorary LL.D degree, University of Hawaii
1960-1965 President, University of Hawaii Foundation
1966 Member, Trade missions to Guyana, Surinam and Netherlands Antilles, Trade Development Bureau, United States Department of Commerce
1966-1967 Director, surveys for airlines serving Hawaii
1967, 1970 Consultant and Coordinator for Rehabilitation, Government of Alaska
1968-1969 Vice President, University of Alaska
1970-1971 Consultant on economy of Alaska, Government of Alaska
1971 Author, Growth Potential of the Interiors of Alaska
1983 June 14 Died, Pine Bluff, Arkansas
SERIES DESCRIPTION
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1946-1983 (Box 1)
  Announcements, certificates, clippings, fraternity membership card, memoranda, notes, obituary and press releases, arranged alphabetically by physical form
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1947-1969 (Boxes 2-6)
  Letters arranged alphabetically by correspondent. Includes a few letters neither from nor to James Shoemaker
- SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, 1924-1968 (Boxes 7-8)
  Articles, conference papers, congressional testimony, notes, outlines, speeches, and related correspondence and press releases arranged chronologically by title
- UNITED STATES GOVERNMENT OFFICE FILE, 1941-1961 (Boxes 9-11)
  Charts, correspondence, handbooks, language guides, maps, memoranda, military dictionary, notes, pamphlets, printed matter, and reports relating to James Shoemaker's service in the army during the Second World War, arranged chronologically by the names of the departments and then by physical form. Also includes the records relating to his participation in the post-war years in the United States navy missions, military government in Korea, and the National Security Resources Board under Presidents Harry Truman and Dwight Eisenhower
- BANK OF HAWAII OFFICE FILE, 1946-1969 (Boxes 11-13)
  Clippings, newsletters, notes, printed matter, press releases, reports, and statements, relating to Hawaii and to James Shoemaker's position as vice-president at the Bank of Hawaii, and to the 100th anniversary celebration of diplomatic relations between Japan and the United States, arranged alphabetically by physical form. Includes correspondence with the president of the Bank of Hawaii
- SUBJECT FILE, 1942-1970 (Box 14)
  Brochures, correspondence, memoranda, newsletters, press releases, printed matter, programs, reports, statements, arranged alphabetically by subject
- OVERSIZE MATERIAL, 1924-1942 (Box 15)
  Certificate for the degree of Master of Arts from the University of Iowa, 1924
- PHOTOGRAPHS, 1954-1958 (Photo file)
  5 prints depicting James Shoemaker with other unidentified individuals
CONTAINER LIST
- BIOGRAPHICAL FILE, 1946-1983
  See also OVERSIZE MATERIAL
  - Announcements (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Certificates (Folder 2)
  - Clippings (Folder 3)
  - Fraternity membership card (Folder 4)
  - Memoranda (Folder 5)
  - Notes. Holograph (Folder 6)
  - Obituary (Folder 7)
  - Press releases (Folder 8)
  - Printed matter (Folder 9)
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1947-1969
  - A and W Root Beer Co. (R. L. Burk, Leonard Withington), 1958. Includes correspondence with Drew Bernard (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Adams, E. Sherman, 1956 (Folder 2)
  - Adams, H. H., 1962 (Folder 3)
  - Adams, Mrs. James P., 1969 (Folder 4)
  - Adler, Jacob, 1961 (Folder 5)
  - Akana, F. Lang, 1958 (Folder 6)
  - Aliber, Robert, 1962 (Folder 7)
  - Aller, Curtis, 1960 (Folder 8)
  - Arita, M., 1963 (Folder 9)
  - Ariyoshi, George R., 1963 (Folder 10)
  - Avnon, Yaakov, 1959-1960 (Folder 11)
  - Baker, William E., 1960 (Folder 12)
  - Bakkum, Glenn A., 1960 (Folder 13)
  - Barnes, Wendell B., 1960 (Folder 14)
  - Batt, William L., 1961 (Folder 15)
  - Beatty, Mrs. Willard, 1969 (Folder 16)
  - Beaumont, Richard A., 1963 (Folder 17)
  - Behrman, Jack N., 1962 (Folder 18)
  - Bell, James Washington, 1960 (Folder 19)
  - Berkeley, Peter J., 1962 (Folder 20)
  - Bernice P. Bishop Museum (H. E. Duff Dayash, Roland W. Force), 1962. Includes correspondence with J. C. Beaglehole (Folder 21)
  - Berridge, William A., 1959 (Folder 22)
  - Beverley, James R., 1958-1962 (Folder 23)
  - Biggs, William R., 1956 (Folder 24)
  - Blackford, Charles E., III, 1965 (Folder 25)
  - Blaisdell, Allen C., 1960 (Folder 26)
  - Blaisdell, Thomas, 1960 (Folder 27)
  - Bland, Eugene H., 1963 (Folder 28)
  - Boekel, William A., 1958-1966 (Folder 29)
  - Bogie, William P., 1965 (Folder 30)
  - Borns, Charles R., 1965 (Folder 31)
  - Brainard, Scott B., 1959 (Folder 32)
  - Bridgeman, Mr. and Mrs. Howard, 1959-1960 (Folder 33)
  - Brodie, S. L., 1969 (Folder 34)
  - Brofman, David, 1962 (Folder 35)
  - Brown, Robert L., 1964 (Folder 36)
  - Bruner, Mr. and Mrs. Glen, 1962-1965 (Folder 37)
  - Buchanan, C. A., 1963 (Folder 38)
  - Bulugh? Thomas, 1959 (Folder 39)
  - Bureau of Business Research, 1962 (Folder 40)
  - Buscher, Charles B., 1963 (Folder 41)
  - Butts, Halleck, 1959 (Folder 42)
  - Cadagan, C. C., 1963 (Folder 43)
  - Cameron, Mr. and Mrs. J. Walter, 1959-1969 (Folder 44)
  - Cannon, Douglas V., 1962 (Folder 45)
  - Canzoneri, Mr. and Mrs. Vincent, 1961 (Folder 46)
  - Carmichael, Leonard, 1959 (Folder 47)
  - Carswell, Lloyd B., 1960 (Folder 48)
  - Castle and Cooke, Inc. (A. O. Marrack, Frederick Simpich, Jr.), 1960. Includes correspondence with Matson Navigation Company, Textiles Clisa S. A. (Folder 49)
  - Chamber of Commerce of Honolulu (J. Ballard Atherton, Richard A. Cooke, Jr., Y. Baron Goto, Masaru Sumida), 1958 (Folder 50)
  - Chandler, Lester V., 1959 (Folder 51)
  - Chaplin, George, 1961-1963 (Folder 52)
  - Chapson, Mrs. Harold B., 1963 (Folder 53)
  - Char, W. S., 1965 (Folder 54)
  - Chaturvedi, K. S., 1959 (Folder 55)
  - Chawner, Lowell, 1960 (Folder 56)
  - Christie, Walter, 1958 (Folder 57)
  - Chun, Richard, 1958 (Folder 58)
  - Clague, Ewan, 1960 (Folder 59)
  - Clark, Blake, 1959 (Folder 60)
  - Clark, Don H., 1959 (Folder 61)
  - Clarke, F. Maurice, 1965-1966 (Folder 62)
  - Clement, Harry G., 1959-1962 (Folder 63)
  - Clement, Norman P., Jr., 1963 (Folder 64)
  - Cogswell, William O., 1959. Letter written to Noble Shropshire (Folder 65)
  - Committee for Economic Development (Dorothy Green, Robert F. Lenhart, Porter McKeever, Alfred C. Neal, Herbert Stein), 1958-1962 (Folder 66)
  - Community Foundation Scholarship Committee, 1957-1958 (Folder 67)
  - Conant, Melvin, 1960-1963 (Folder 68)
  - Condliffe, Mr. and Mrs. J. B., 1961-1966. Includes copy of a letter by R. M. Fujii (Folder 69)
  - Cooke, Richard A., 1958-1965 (Folder 70)
  - Coolidge, Harold J., 1962 (Folder 71)
  - Coombs, Philip H., 1962 (Folder 72)
  - Copland, Douglas, Sir, 1961 (Folder 73)
  - Corstorphine, J. B., 1958 (Folder 74)
  - Cotten, Mr. and Mrs. William, 1960 (Folder 75)
  - Cover, John, 1960-1961 (Folder 76)
  - Cowen, Myron M., 1959 (Folder 77)
  - Cox, William L., 1960 (Folder 78)
  - Craig, Robert S., 1959 (Folder 79)
  - Crampon, Jack, 1959 (Folder 80)
  - Creighton, William S., 1959 (Folder 81)
  - Crossley, Randolph, 1960 (Folder 82)
  - Cruzc, Luzmila, 1960 (Folder 83)
  - Cue, Vincent W., 1964 (Folder 84)
  - Dakin, Allen W., 1960 (Folder 85)
  - Damon, C. F., Jr., 1962 (Folder 86)
  - Daniels, Draper, 1962 (Folder 87)
  - Davenport, Donald H., 1961 (Folder 88)
  - David, Donald K., 1959 (Folder 89)
  - Davies, Larry, 1963 (Folder 90)
  - Davis, J. Lionberger, 1959 (Folder 91)
  - Day, A. Grove, 1960 (Folder 92)
  - De Chazeau, Melville, 1962 (Folder 93)
  - Decker, O. Paul, 1956 (Folder 94)
  - De la Rue, Sidney, 1958-1959 (Folder 95)
  - Dillard, Hardy C., 1959-1963. Includes a letter from H. William Burgess (Folder 96)
  - Dillingham, Benjamin F., II, 1962 (Folder 97)
  - Dwyre, Jack G., 1960 (Folder 98)
  - Earley, James S., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Egan, Mark, 1961-1963 (Folder 2)
  - Egan, William A., 1961 (Folder 3)
  - Elliott, D. C., 1956 (Folder 4)
  - Elliott, John C., 1962 (Folder 5)
  - Ellsworth, Paul, 1963 (Folder 6)
  - Emerson, John, 1960 (Folder 7)
  - Emmerson, John K., 1960-1963 (Folder 8)
  - Engle, N. H., 1959 (Folder 9)
  - Evans, J. D., 1958-1964 (Folder 10)
  - Evans, W. Duane, 1960-1962 (Folder 11)
  - Fairbank, John K., 1959-1960 (Folder 12)
  - Faris, R. E. L., 1962 (Folder 13)
  - Farley, Hugh D., 1959 (Folder 14)
  - Feirer, Albert J., 1962 (Folder 15)
  - Ferber, Robert, 1962-1963 (Folder 16)
  - Fern, Stewart, 1958 (Folder 17)
  - Finegan, Hazel Aldrich (Mrs. Edward), 1953 (Folder 18)
  - Finnerud, Kenneth P., 1968 (Folder 19)
  - Fletcher, W. Donald, 1962-1966 (Folder 20)
  - Flieder, Gerald L., 1963 (Folder 21)
  - Fong, H. D., 1961 (Folder 22)
  - Fong, Hiram L., 1960-1962 (Folder 23)
  - Forbes, Theodore W., 1960-1961 (Folder 24)
  - Frazier, Mrs. George, 1962 (Folder 25)
  - Fujinaga, Jean, 1963 (Folder 26)
  - Fukunaga, George, 1961 (Folder 27)
  - Fukutomi, Shozaburo, 1966 (Folder 28)
  - Garnsey, Mr. and Mrs. M. E., 1969 (Folder 29)
  - George, Allan C., 1965 (Folder 30)
  - Getz, J. G., Jr., 1961 (Folder 31)
  - Gibbs, Gordon, 1963-1965 (Folder 32)
  - Gilman, Mr. and Mrs. Roy, 1969 (Folder 33)
  - Gima, Richard S., 1959 (Folder 34)
  - Goding, Wilford, 1961-1965 (Folder 35)
  - Gomberg, Ephraim R., 1960 (Folder 36)
  - Goncharoff, Nicholas, 1959-1961 (Folder 37)
  - Gootenberg, Roy F., 1963-1966 (Folder 38)
  - Gose, George, 1960 (Folder 39)
  - Goto, Y. Baron, 1958 (Folder 40)
  - Grether, E. T., 1960 (Folder 41)
  - Groundfest, Dave, 1962 (Folder 42)
  - Grove, David L., 1956 (Folder 43)
  - Guild, Robert W., 1963 (Folder 44)
  - Gulley, Lee R., 1961 (Folder 45)
  - Halsted, S. A., 1963 (Folder 46)
  - Hamilton, Thomas H., 1963-1965 (Folder 47)
  - Hanan, Mr. and Mrs. Vance A., 1964 (Folder 48)
  - Hara, Stanley I., 1963 (Folder 49)
  - Hardenbrook, D. J., 1962-1963 (Folder 50)
  - Haring, Robert C., 1969 (Folder 51)
  - Harper's Magazine (Rose Daly, John Fischer), 1959-1962 (Folder 52)
  - Harrington, Fred H., 1962 (Folder 53)
  - Harris, Britton, 1960 (Folder 54)
  - Hart, James A., 1961 (Folder 55)
  - Harvey, John, 1960 (Folder 56)
  - Harwood, E. C., 1959 (Folder 57)
  - Hasegawa, Robert K., 1960 (Folder 58)
  - Hawaii Farm Bureau Federation (Wallace Nitta, Masaru Sumida), 1965-1966. Includes correspondence with Allan Grant, President, California Farm Bureau Federation (Folder 59)
  - Hawaiian Evangelical Association of Congregational Christian Churches (Joseph J. Bevilacqua, Reginald W. Carter, Harry S. Kennedy, Harry S. Komuro), 1962 (Folder 60)
  - Hazama, Dorothy, 1965 (Folder 61)
  - Hazard, Patrick D., 1961-1963 (Folder 62)
  - Hecht, Frank A., 1963 (Folder 63)
  - Henderson, C. M., 1958 (Folder 64)
  - Henning, James F., 1962-1963 (Folder 65)
  - Hensley, Roy J., 1963 (Folder 66)
  - Hersey, Lewis G., 1959 (Folder 67)
  - Hersey, Nelson, 1969 (Folder 68)
  - Hillen, William G., 1959-1961 (Folder 69)
  - Hilpert, Fred S., 1956 (Folder 70)
  - Hindle, W. H. N., 1961 (Folder 71)
  - Hinrichs, A. F., 1946-1969 (Folder 72)
  - Hiratsuka, Taizo, 1960 (Folder 73)
  - Hiscock, Ira V., 1959 (Folder 74)
  - Ho, Raymond Y. C., 1962-1963 (Folder 75)
  - Hobson, Jesse, 1956-1959 (Folder 76)
  - Hoeber, R. C., 1966 (Folder 77)
  - Holder, Reginald F., 1965-1966 (Folder 78)
  - Holland, W. L., 1947 (Folder 79)
  - Holmes, William John, 1961. Includes a printed article (Folder 80)
  - Holtzman, Richard E., 1965 (Folder 81)
  - Hopkins, Russell H., 1963 (Folder 82)
  - Horii, Henry F., 1963 (Folder 83)
  - Hosken, William E., 1960 (Folder 84)
  - Hoslett, Schuyler, 1966 (Folder 85)
  - House of Representatives, Territory of Hawaii (Nelson K. Doi, Stanley I. Hara), 1959 (Folder 86)
  - Huang, Kai-Loo, 1966. Includes letters from George H. Gadbois, Jr., F. J. Moore (Folder 87)
  - Huetz de Lemps, Christian, 1964 (Folder 88)
  - Hunsberger, Warren S., 1963 (Folder 89)
  - Hunt, Snowden M., 1962 (Folder 90)
  - Huston, Mr. and Mrs. F. Craig, 1965 (Folder 91)
  - Ingram, James C., 1958-1959 (Folder 92)
  - Ishida, Jack, 1956-1963. Includes correspondence with Fujio Matsuda, Kengo Otagaki (Folder 93)
  - Ishizaka, T., 1960-1961 (Folder 94)
  - Iwasa, Yoshizane, 1962-1964 (Folder 95)
  - Jackson, Alice, 1963 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Janssen, J. F., 1963 (Folder 2)
  - Japan National Tourist Association (Yoshinori Mori, Shoji Tanaka), 1963 (Folder 3)
  - Jenkins, W. P., 1959 (Folder 4)
  - Johnson, Edgar and Virginia, 1959-1969 (Folder 5)
  - Johnson, Norris O., 1956 (Folder 6)
  - Johnson, Ralph B., 1961 (Folder 7)
  - Jones, Howard P., 1965-1966. Includes correspondence with Thomas H. Hamilton, Schuyler D. Hoslett (Folder 8)
  - Juda, Felix, 1966 (Folder 9)
  - Kagan, Sioma, 1961 (Folder 10)
  - Kanakanui, William I., 1962 (Folder 11)
  - Kanninen, T. P., 1963 (Folder 12)
  - Kasdon, Mrs. Lawrence M., 1966 (Folder 13)
  - Kaufmann, Mr. and Mrs. Paul T., 1966 (Folder 14)
  - Kawano, Hideo, 1959 (Folder 15)
  - Kawasaki, Rae, 1965 (Folder 16)
  - Keezer, Dexter M., 1959 (Folder 17)
  - Kelley, Roy C., 1960 (Folder 18)
  - Kennedy, David M., 1956 (Folder 19)
  - Kennedy, Robert, 1962 (Folder 20)
  - Kerr, Alex M., n.d. (Folder 21)
  - Khanna, K. L., 1962-1966 (Folder 22)
  - Kiaer, Hans Th., 1959 (Folder 23)
  - Kilgare, Bishop M., 1963 (Folder 24)
  - Killough, Hugh and Lucy, 1969 (Folder 25)
  - Kirkland, Edward C., 1962 (Folder 26)
  - Kiuchi, Nobutane, 1962-1963 (Folder 27)
  - Knapp, J. Burke, 1961 (Folder 28)
  - Knight, Frank H., 1959 (Folder 29)
  - Kobayashi, James J., 1962 (Folder 30)
  - Komuro, Harry S., 1961 (Folder 31)
  - Konagawa? Lisa Kei, 1965 (Holograph) (Folder 32)
  - Korol, Bea (Mrs. A.), 1963 (Folder 33)
  - Kossoris, M. D., 1961-1963 (Folder 34)
  - Kreager, H. Dewayne, 1962-1966 (Folder 35)
  - Krider, Walter W., 1964 (Folder 36)
  - Kurata, Paul M., 1963 (Folder 37)
  - Kuwahara, John, 1963 (Folder 38)
  - Landrum, James E., Jr., 1966 (Folder 39)
  - Lane, L. W., Jr., 1959-1965 (Folder 40)
  - Laureta, Alfred, 1964 (Folder 41)
  - Layton, Marguerite Cadwallader, 1960 (Folder 42)
  - LeDioyt, Glenn H., 1966 (Folder 43)
  - Lee, Mark W., 1969 (Folder 44)
  - Lee, Michael E., 1960 (Folder 45)
  - Lee, Mr. and Mrs. George, 1963 (Folder 46)
  - Leech, Virginia, 1963 (Folder 47)
  - Leffingwell, Roy J., 1959 (Folder 48)
  - Lemmon, Cyril, 1960 (Folder 49)
  - Leonard, Warren H., 1959 (Folder 50)
  - Lewendal, Lars, 1963 (Folder 51)
  - Lewis, Arthur D., 1960 (Folder 52)
  - Lewis, Frederick H., 1960-1962 (Folder 53)
  - Lewis, James H., 1960 (Folder 54)
  - Lind, Katherine (Mrs. A. W.), 1963 (Folder 55)
  - Little, Herbert S., 1960 (Folder 56)
  - Livingston, S. Morris, 1960 (Folder 57)
  - Lohani, K., 1960 (Folder 58)
  - Long, Oren E., 1962 (Folder 59)
  - Loveless, Wendell P., 1963 (Folder 60)
  - Lovewell, Paul J., 1966 (Folder 61)
  - Low, Don, 1965 (Folder 62)
  - Lowrey, David M., 1964-1965. Includes correspondence with Asa B. Davis, Evelyn Nazaruk (Folder 63)
  - Luc, Mr. and Mrs. Robert, 1962 (Folder 64)
  - Lucas, B., 1958 (Holograph) (Folder 65)
  - Lucas, P. A., 1963 (Folder 66)
  - Lundy, Robert L., 1963 (Folder 67)
  - Lutzky, Seymour, 1962 (Folder 68)
  - Lyons, Louis M., 1958 (Folder 69)
  - Lyons, Raymond R., 1960 (Folder 70)
  - McCoy, F. W., 1965 (Folder 71)
  - McCrea, William S., 1965-1966 (Folder 72)
  - McCune, Shannon, 1959-1965 (Folder 73)
  - McCutcheon, William C., Jr., 1955 (Folder 74)
  - McDermott, Edward A., 1963-1965 (Folder 75)
  - McGrew, Mr. and Mrs. William, 1960 (Folder 76)
  - McInroe, Aliceon, 1958 (Folder 77)
  - McLane, George H., 1961 (Folder 78)
  - McNamara, Robert S., 1963 (Folder 79)
  - McNealy, R. J., 1963 (Folder 80)
  - McQuaid, William J., 1965 (Folder 81)
  - Mack, Joseph A., 1960 (Folder 82)
  - Mackey, Robert R., 1964 (Folder 83)
  - Mann, Shivinderpal Singh, 1962 (Folder 84)
  - Mark, Shelley M., 1961 (Folder 85)
  - Marquis - Who's Who, Inc., 1963 (Folder 86)
  - Marshall, R. W., 1958 (Folder 87)
  - Martin, Preston, 1960 (Folder 88)
  - Mason, Edward, 1962 (Folder 89)
  - Mathison, J., 1958. Includes a letter from W. J. Mullahey (Folder 90)
  - Matthew, Christian J., 1963 (Folder 91)
  - Mau, William K. H., 1964 (Folder 92)
  - Maxey, Bob, 1963 (Folder 93)
  - Menard, Iva, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Meredith, L. Douglas, 1963 (Folder 2)
  - Merrill, Edward A., 1965 (Folder 3)
  - Michener, Dwight W., 1956 (Folder 4)
  - Midkiff, Frank E., 1963 (Folder 5)
  - Miller, John, 1965 (Folder 6)
  - Mills, A. C., 1960 (Folder 7)
  - Miyake, Howard Y., 1959 (Folder 8)
  - Miyamoto, Stanley, 1960 (Folder 9)
  - Moore, Charles A., 1961-1962 (Folder 10)
  - Moore, Franklin, 1963-1966 (Folder 11)
  - Moosbrugger, Edward, 1963 (Folder 12)
  - Morgan Guaranty Trust Company (DeWitt Peterkin, Jr., Fred Simmons), 1960-1965 (Folder 13)
  - Morimoto, Yoshio, 1963 (Folder 14)
  - Moriwaki, Sharon, 1963 (Folder 15)
  - Morris, K. J., 1958. Includes holograph note (Folder 16)
  - Moscoso, Teodoro, 1960 (Folder 17)
  - Moses, Mr. and Mrs. S. L., 1964-1965 (Folder 18)
  - Mullahey, W. J., 1962 (Folder 19)
  - Mullen, Martha Lee (Mrs. John W.), 1964 (Folder 20)
  - Murphy, Laurel, 1969 (Folder 21)
  - Murphy, Lester P., 1965 (Folder 22)
  - Nagasaki Prefectural Government (Shozaburo Fukutomi, Hiromi Nakamura, Katsuya Sato), 1960-1965 (Folder 23)
  - Nagata, Albert T., 1963-1965 (Folder 24)
  - Naito, Yukio, 1964 (Folder 25)
  - Nakamoto, George, 1959 (Folder 26)
  - Nakamura, Keisuke, 1963 (Folder 27)
  - Nickerson, Thomas, 1960 (Folder 28)
  - Nip, Kenneth, 1957-1958 (Folder 29)
  - Novogrod, R. Joseph, 1959 (Folder 30)
  - Nuha, Sam, 1958 (Folder 31)
  - Oakley, Mr. and Mrs. C. O., 1959-1965 (Folder 32)
  - Odell, William R., 1959-1962 (Folder 33)
  - Ogata, Thomas S., 1964 (Folder 34)
  - Ogawa, Seido, 1963-1965 (Folder 35)
  - Ono, Shinji, 1961 (in Japanese) (Folder 36)
  - Ortlieb, David W., 1966 (Folder 37)
  - Pacific Consultants (Robert Fairbank), 1959. Includes correspondence with Henry J. Kaiser, Matson Navigation Company (Folder 38)
  - Papez, D. W., 1962 (Folder 39)
  - Perrine, J. O., 1961 (Folder 40)
  - Peterson, R. A., 1962-1969 (Folder 41)
  - Pickup, Robert E., 1962-1963. Includes correspondence with Fred W. Bennion (Folder 42)
  - Pierce, Howard, 1963 (Folder 43)
  - Porter, Wigglesworth and Company (Rolf Porter, J. W. Whitcombe, Noel Whitcombe), 1958-1966 (Folder 44)
  - Putnam, Mr. and Mrs. Charles W., 1965 (Folder 45)
  - Quinn, William F., 1959-1961 (Folder 46)
  - Quon, Joseph B., 1963 (Folder 47)
  - Remer, Carl, 1961-1966 (Folder 48)
  - Resources for the Future, Inc. (Joseph Fisher, Harvey S. Perloff), 1960 (Folder 49)
  - Rice, Eugene R., 1962 (Folder 50)
  - Rice, Stuart A., 1962 (Folder 51)
  - Ricker, Frank G., 1958 (Folder 52)
  - Rieck, Frederick C., 1956 (Folder 53)
  - Ritterhoff, Robert F., 1962 (Folder 54)
  - Rizzo, Frank, 1957-1963 (Folder 55)
  - Robbins, J. Stanton, 1965-1966 (Folder 56)
  - Roberts, Harold S., 1958 (Folder 57)
  - Robinson, T. G., 1958 (Folder 58)
  - Robison, H. E., 1959-1966 (Folder 59)
  - Roca, Gaspar, Jr., 1960 (Folder 60)
  - Rogers, George W., 1960-1961 (Folder 61)
  - Roterus, Victor, 1960 (Folder 62)
  - Rouzitsky, Peter M., 1959 (Folder 63)
  - Rubicam, Harry C., Jr., 1959 (Folder 64)
  - Ruiz, Leopoldo, 1963 (Folder 65)
  - Sarles, Harvey J., 1961 (Folder 66)
  - Saunders, E. C., 1962 (Folder 67)
  - Schnetz, Henry O., 1963 (Folder 68)
  - Schwartz, Charles F., 1963 (Folder 69)
  - Scott, Burton A., Jr., 1959 (Folder 70)
  - Scott, Walter B., 1960 (Folder 71)
  - Serrao, John A., 1961 (Folder 72)
  - Shedd, Jesse E., 1960 (Folder 73)
  - Sherbert, Paul C., 1960 (Folder 74)
  - Sheu, Albert Ke-sheng, 1966 (Folder 75)
  - Shoemaker, Mr. and Mrs. Paul B., 1962-1965 (Folder 76)
  - Shuck, L. Edward, Jr., 1958 (Folder 77)
  - Simpson, Ann B. (Mrs. John G.), 1958 (Folder 78)
  - Sinclair, Mr. and Mrs. Gregg, 1960 (Folder 79)
  - Skatvold, Jerald H., 1965 (Folder 80)
  - Smart, Mr. and Mrs. Antony P., 1963 (Folder 81)
  - Smart, Richard, 1961 (Folder 82)
  - Smith, Arthur A., 1956 (Folder 83)
  - Smith, Mr. and Mrs. Bradford, 1959-1963 (Folder 84)
  - Smith, Courtney, 1963 (Folder 85)